Scientists have created by accident an enzyme that breaks down plastic drinks bottles.
科学家无意中造出了一种能分解塑料饮料瓶的酶。
The breakthrough could help solve the global plastic pollution crisis by enabling for the first time the full recycling of bottles.
这一突破或许能首次实现瓶子的完全回收，从而有助于解决全球塑料污染危机。
The new research was spurred by the discovery in 2016 of the first bacterium that had naturally evolved to eat plastic at a waste dump in Japan.
推动这项新研究的，是2016年的一项发现：在日本的一个垃圾场，人们找到了首个经自然进化而能吃塑料的细菌。
Scientists have now revealed the detailed structure of the crucial enzyme produced by the bug.
这种细菌会产生一种关键的酶，如今科学家已经揭示出这种酶的详细结构。
An international team then adjusted the enzyme to see how it had evolved, but tests showed they had accidentally made the molecule even better at breaking down the plastic used for drinks bottles.
随后，一个国际团队调整了这种酶，想看看它是如何进化而来的，但测试表明，他们无意中让这种酶分子更加擅长分解制作饮料瓶的塑料了。
“What actually turned out was we improved the enzyme, which was a bit of a shock,” said head researcher Prof. McGeehan, at the University of Portsmouth, UK.
“实际的结果是，我们改进了这种酶，这让人有点震惊。”英国朴茨茅斯大学的首席研究员麦吉汉教授说。
Currently, the enzyme takes a few days to start breaking down the plastic, far faster than the centuries it takes in the oceans, but the researchers are optimistic this can be speeded up even further and become a viable large-scale process.
目前，这种酶需要几天才开始分解塑料，比塑料在海洋中分解所需的几百年快得多；不过研究人员乐观地认为，这一过程还能再进一步加快，并成为一种可行的大规模工艺。
“What we are hoping to do is use this enzyme to turn this plastic back into its original components, so we can literally recycle it back to plastic,” said McGeehan.
“我们希望用这种酶把这种塑料还原成原来的成分，这样就能真正把它回收再造成塑料。”麦吉汉说。
“It means we won’t need to dig up any more oil and, fundamentally, it should reduce the amount of plastic in the environment.”
“这意味着我们将不必再开采更多石油，而且从根本上说，这应该会减少环境中塑料的数量。”
About 1 million plastic bottles are sold each minute around the globe and, with just 14% recycled, many end up in the oceans where they have polluted even the remotest parts, harming marine life and potentially people who eat seafood.
全球每分钟大约售出100万个塑料瓶，其中只有14%得到回收，许多最终流入海洋，甚至已经污染了最偏远的海域，危害海洋生物，还可能危害吃海鲜的人。
“Plastic is incredibly resistant to degradation,” said McGeehan.
“塑料极其难以降解。”麦吉汉说。
“It is one of these wonder materials that have been made a little bit too well.”
“有些神奇材料造得有点太好了，它就是其中之一。”
Currently those bottles that are recycled can only be turned into opaque fibres for clothing or carpets, while the new enzyme indicates a way to recycle old clear plastic bottles back into new clear plastic bottles.
目前，回收的瓶子只能制成不透明的纤维，用来做衣服或地毯；而这种新酶指明了一条途径，可以把透明的旧塑料瓶回收再造成透明的新塑料瓶。
“You are always up against the fact that oil is cheap, so plastic is cheap,” said McGeehan.
“你总是要面对这样一个事实：石油便宜，所以塑料也便宜。”麦吉汉说。
“It is so easy for manufacturers to generate more of that stuff, rather than even try to recycle, but I believe there is a public interest here: perception is changing so much that companies are starting to look at how they can properly recycle these bottles.”
“对制造商来说，只管多生产一些这种东西，连回收都不去尝试，实在太容易了；但我相信，公众是关心这件事的：人们的看法正在发生很大的变化，以至于企业开始研究怎样才能妥善回收这些瓶子。”
Prof. Adisa Azapagic, at the University of Manchester in the UK, agreed the enzyme could be useful but added: “A full life-cycle assessment would be needed to ensure that the technology does not solve one environmental problem—waste—at the expense of others, including additional greenhouse gas emissions.”
英国曼彻斯特大学的阿迪萨·阿扎帕吉克教授认同这种酶可能有用，但补充说：“需要做一次完整的生命周期评估，以确保这项技术在解决废弃物这一环境问题的同时，不会以其他环境问题为代价，其中包括额外的温室气体排放。”